clarizen.com 2018-12-24

# Online Project Management Software Privacy Policy | Clarizen

## Privacy Policy

Effective date: 5/25/2018

#### This privacy policy has been created to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used by Clarizen’s services, which include its site at [clarizen.com](http://clarizen.com/) as well as its applications for mobile devices and social networks (collectively, the “Site” or “Services”).

PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context.

PII, as used in the European Union, is any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (‘data subject’); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural, or social identity of that natural person

Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information that is voluntarily submitted or collected automatically when accessing the Services.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on the “Effective date” noted above. Clarizen reserves the right to change, modify or amend this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in our privacy practices. You are encouraged to review this Privacy Policy periodically and to check the “Effective date” at the top of this Privacy Policy for the most recent version, to inform yourself about how your PII is collected, used, and shared when you use the Services.

**If you do not agree with these terms, please do not access, or use the Services.**

### What personal information do we collect?

In order to enable visitors of our Services to see certain pages, when specifically requested by such visitors, we may require the user to provide contact information, (including but not limited to name and e-mail address). The information collected shall be used for the purposes providing you with email support and in order to allow Clarizen to contact you, from time to time, via email communication, with news and updates about services, products, and offerings (such as: a newsletter, new releases, new features, special offers etc.).

If you wish, at any time, to remove your email address from any of the above mentioned email mailing lists and stop receiving future email communications from us, other than the emails directly related to the Service functionality, you may unsubscribe by sending an email to: [info@clarizen.com](mailto:info@clarizen.com). For your convenience, email communication from us contains instructions regarding how to unsubscribe from our e-mail mailing lists.

Contact information is information such as your name or mailing address that can be used to uniquely identify you. In order to use certain Services and/or receive newsletters or commercial offers, you must provide contact information.

Additionally, as you navigate through and interact with the website, we may use automatic data collection technologies to collect the following information about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns:

  * details of your visits to our website, including traffic data, geolocation data, logs, what website you viewed immediately prior to visiting our website, what search engine and search keywords you may have used to get to our website, and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the website; and
  * information about your computer and internet connection, specifically your IP address operating system and browser type.

We also may use these technologies to collect information about your online activities over time and across third party websites or other online services (behavioral tracking).

The information we collect automatically includes Personal Data and/or we may maintain it or associate it with Personal Data we collect in other ways or receive from third parties.  It helps us to improve our website and to deliver a better and more personalized service, enabling us to:

  * estimate our audience size and usage patterns;
  * store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our website according to your individual interests;
  * speed up your searches; and
  * recognize you when you return to our website.

### When do we collect information?

We collect information from you when you register on our site, access our services, subscribe to a newsletter, fill out a form, or enter information on our site.

### How do we use your information?

We may use the information we collect from you in the following ways:

  * To personalize user’s experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested or have directly requested from us.
  * To improve our Services in order to better serve you.
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.
  * To administer surveys or other site features.
  * To quickly process your transactions.
  * To send periodic emails regarding your products and services.

### How do we protect visitor information?

Clarizen employs a dedicated security team that utilizes industry best practices and best of breed technology to manage security of our infrastructure and your data.  Clarizen undergoes an annual independent third-party assessment, performs an annual data privacy impact assessment, and maintains ISO 27001:2013 certification.

All your contact information, including, but not limited to, your name, address, telephone number, email address, is held in strict confidence. This information is collected for the primarily purposes of enabling you to receive the Services requested by you.

### Security scanning

Your personal information is encrypted and stored behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive information you supply is encrypted “in transit,” and “at rest.”

We implement a variety of security measures when a user enters, submits, or accesses their information to maintain the safety of your personal information.

Although we take every possible measure to provide secure Services threats are constantly evolving, and new risks appear regularly and therefore Clarizen cannot be liable for service interruptions, intrusions, errors, loss of data, or any other interference with the use of the Services as a result of security related incidents.

### Do we use cookies?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (with your permission) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and remember certain information. Cookies are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current Site activity,

### We use cookies to:

  * Understand and save user’s preferences for future visits, which enables us to provide you with improved services.
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies, you will still be able to access our site, but some features may be disabled and some of our services may not function properly.

### Third party disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information (PII) unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our Services, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential and secured in compliance with Clarizen policies.

We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to protect ourselves from liability, or to comply with law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety. We may also disclose your personal information to the extent necessary in connection with a merger, acquisition, liquidation, or bankruptcy of the company.

Non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

We use the following third party services to help us provide you with the services and to improve our website and understand our users:

  * Google Analytics and Other Analytics Providers. We may use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”) to collect certain information relating to your use of the website.  Google Analytics uses cookies as described above.  You can find out more about how Google uses data when you visit our website by visiting “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps” (located at [google.com/policies/privacy/partners](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners));
  * Other Services. We also use other third party providers to help us understand our users and to help us analyze and debug errors you may encounter when using our website and our Sensors.  These organizations are under contractual obligations to use this data only for providing the services to us and to maintain this information strictly confidential.  These third parties may, however, aggregate the information it collects with information from their other customers for their own purposes.

### Third party links

Links to third party websites are provided as a convenience to you. Such linked sites are outside of our control and responsibility and are not covered by this policy. If you use any such linked sites, you should consult the privacy policies posted on those websites.

### Do-Not-Track signals

Because there is not yet a consensus on how companies should respond to web browser-based or other “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) mechanisms, we currently do not respond to web browser DNT signals that provide a method to opt out of the collection of information about online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services. We may revisit our policy on responding to these signals, in which case we will post a revised privacy policy on this site.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites or mobile applications collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy.

See more at: //[consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf](http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf)

According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:

  * Users can visit our site anonymously, but this will limit our ability to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested, or for which you have paid and subscribed to.
  * Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.
  * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.
  * Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes on our Privacy Policy page
  * Users are able to change their personal information

By emailing us

  * By calling us
  * By contacting their account representatives.

### Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:

  * We will notify the users via email, or preferred method of communication.
  * We will notify the users via in-site notification.

### Limitation of liability

Under no circumstances, including but not limited to negligence, shall we be liable for any special or consequential damages that results from the use of, or the inability to use, the website and the materials in it.

Without derogating the aforementioned, in no event shall our total liability exceed the amount paid by you, if any, for accessing the site.

### Notice to California residents re: direct marketing

Pursuant to California Civil Code Section 1798.83, residents of the State of California have the right to request from companies conducting business in California certain information regarding disclosure within the immediately preceding calendar year of that California resident’s personal information to third parties (and in some cases affiliates) for their direct marketing purposes.

Alternatively, the law provides that a company may comply, as Clarizen does, by disclosing in its privacy policy that it provides consumers with a choice (opt-out or opt-in) regarding sharing personal information with third parties and affiliates for those third parties’ and affiliates’ direct marketing purposes, and information on how to exercise that choice. At this time, we do not share personally identifiable information with third parties or affiliates for those third parties’ or affiliates’ direct marketing purposes. If we do so in the future, Clarizen will provide you with a choice prior to sharing your personally identifiable information with third parties and affiliates for their direct marketing purposes. If you do not opt-in or if you choose to opt-out at the time Clarizen offers that choice, we will not share your information with that identified third party or affiliate for its direct marketing purposes.

If you are a California resident and you have questions about our practices with respect to sharing information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes and your ability to exercise choice, please send your request to the following email address: [info@clarizen.com](mailto:info@clarizen.com) or write to us at the following mailing address. You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field of your e-mail or include it in your writing if you choose to write to us at the designated mailing address. You must include your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year.

### European Union General Data Protection Regulations

If you are in the European Union, the processing of Personal Data is lawful only if it is permitted under the applicable data protection laws. We have a lawful basis for each of our processing activities (except when an exception applies as described below):

  * By using our website, you consent to our collection, use and sharing of your Personal Data as described in this Privacy Policy.  If you do not consent to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the services or website;
  * Legitimate Interests. We will process your Personal Data as necessary for our legitimate interests such as facilitating communication between Clarizen and you and improving our website and IT infrastructure;
  * To Fulfill Our Obligations to You Under Our Contracts. We process your Personal Data in order to fulfill our obligations to you pursuant to our contracts; and
  * As Required by Law. We may also process your Personal Data to respond to legal process, such as subpoenas or as necessary for us to protect our interests or otherwise pursue our legal rights and remedies (for instance, when necessary to prevent or detect fraud, attacks against our network or other criminal and tortious activities), defend litigation and manage complaints or claims.

### YOUR RIGHTS TO YOUR INFORMATION AND ACCESSING AND CORRECTING YOUR INFORMATION

Applicable data protection laws may provide you with certain rights with regard to our processing of your Personal Data.

  * Access and Update. You can review and change your Personal Data by logging into your online account.
  * You have the right to restrict our processing of your Personal Data under certain circumstances.  In particular, you can request we restrict our use of it if you contest its accuracy, if the processing of your Personal Data is determined to be unlawful, or if we no longer need your Personal Data for processing, but we have retained it as permitted by law.
  * You have the right to lodge a complaint with the applicable supervisory authority in your country where you believe your rights under applicable data protection laws have been violated.  However, before doing so, we request that you contact us directly in order to give us an opportunity to work directly with you to resolve any concerns about your privacy.
  * Withdrawal of Consent. To the extent that our processing of your Personal Data is based on your consent, you may withdraw your consent at any time by closing your account.  Withdrawing your consent will not, however, affect the lawfulness of the processing based on your consent before its withdrawal, and it will not affect the lawfulness of our continued processing that is based on any other lawful basis for processing your Personal Data.
  * Right to be Forgotten. You have the right to request that we delete all of your Personal Data.  We will only delete your Personal Data when we no longer have a lawful basis for processing your Personal Data or after a final determination that your Personal Data was unlawfully processed.  We may not accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect.  In all other cases, we will retain your Personal Data as set forth in this Policy.  In addition, we cannot completely delete your Personal Data as some data may rest in previous backups.

How You May Exercise Your Rights.  You may exercise any of the above rights by contacting us through any of the methods below.  If you contact us to exercise any of the foregoing rights, we may ask you for additional information to verify your identity.  We reserve the right to limit or deny your request if you have failed to provide sufficient information to verify your identity or to satisfy our legal and business requirements.

### Children

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. No-one under age 13 may provide any information to or on the Site. If you are under the age of 13, do not register on the Site or use or provide any personal information on or through the Site, including your name, email address or any screen name or user name you may use.

### Contact us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.

**Clarizen**  
2755 Campus Drive, Suite 300  
San Mateo, CA 94403  
USA
